ANTHONY S. DIAZ

21 Beverly Road, Bethpage, NY 11714 | 646-235-3940 | ANTHONY.AD.DIAZ@GMAIL.COM

Professional Summary

Proven Ad Operations leader with over 10 years of experience in system and process implementation, team management and development, cross-functional communication, and industry expertise.

Considered driven, talented, smart and a valuable addition to any team.

Skills

- Ad Platforms: Ad Manager 360 (DFP),
 Campaign Manager (DCM), Adtech,
 LiveRamp
- Digital Marketing Tools: Operative.One, Adobe Audience Manager, Integral Ad Science, Moat, Tradable Bits, Omniture

 Microsoft Office Suite: Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project

Work History

Director Apr 2016 - Current
Viacom New York, NY

- Established a brand new team (Technology & Ad Operations) within Viacom's Audience Science Group and designed various cross-functional policies and procedures for the department.
- Responsible for audience creation and maintenance of first party data across Adobe Audience
 Manager, Facebook Custom Audiences, and YouTube Remarketing Lists to be leveraged for
 various tune-in, retail, and ticket purchase initiatives across the Viacom portfolio with over \$15
 million in revenue per year.
- Ensure necessary audience collection pixels are implemented across Viacom O&O properties along with acquiring necessary approvals from Legal team.
- Managed the implementation of DoubleClick Campaign Manager into Ad Operations, Analytics, and Viacom agency partner workflows. Created training material and ran educational sessions for required users of the platform.
- Drove the development of Viacom activation standards for viewability and brand safety via IAS
 for Viacom agency partners as well as Audience Science marketing efforts. Through team
 monitoring efforts, wasted inventory levels were kept under 10%.
- Maintain ad serving platform relationships including assisting with rate negotiations, maintaining rate cards and expenses, vetting, testing, and on-boarding of advanced capabilities.

Principal Consultant Feb 2014 - Oct 2015

Infinitive New York, NY

 Performed Project Lead duties on audience segmentation initiative to monetize first party data with large APAC publisher utilizing Oracle/BlueKai.

- Provided Ad Operations subject matter expertise and training support for an order management system implementation of Operative.One.
- Assisted with campaign migration tasks and established native advertising work flow procedure for responsive site relaunch project.
- Contributed to the documentation of Ad Operations processes & procedures and best practices to transact on viewability.

Director Feb 2011 - Jan 2014

Sporting News Media

New York, NY

- Led a team of 4 who managed over \$10 million in video, display, and mobile campaigns across SportingNews.com, Goal.com, and Sporting News Media Video Affiliate Partners.
- Oversaw day-to-day operations including staff management, project allocations, discrepancy determination, deadlines, and QA of ad tag implementation across online and mobile platforms.
- Managed remnant partnerships and initiated programmatic/real-time bidding strategies via
 Pubmatic and OpenX in addition to backfill waterfall hierarchy in LiveRail to increase secondary revenue streams by over 60%.
- Project managed ad server migration from DFPP to AdTech, order management system implementation of Operative.One into Ad Operations/Sales/Finance workflows, and data platform management integration of Lotame.

Manager Jun 2010 - Feb 2011

Fox News Digital

New York, NY

- Oversaw a team of 7 (4 Traffickers/3 Coordinators) responsible for trafficking, optimizing, reporting and delivering all National and Remnant online ad campaigns worth over \$40 million.
- Managed internal workflow, communication and relevant systems to minimize discrepancies, while maximizing campaign delivery and booked revenue.
- Interacted with other departments such as: Sales Development, Production, Business Development and other functions to proactively expedite new products to market.
- Ensured new site sections, re-launches, ad creatives, and third-party ad tags undergo a QA
 process to facilitate successful campaign performance.

Senior Manager Jul 2006 - Apr 2010

Sports Illustrated

New York, NY

- Managed an Ad Operations team of 3 Traffickers responsible for handling on-line advertising for SI Digital properties (SI.com, SIKids.com, FanNation.com, and DanPatrick.com).
- Contributed to the achievement of yearly goals of over \$30 million.
- Collaborated with Marketing, Design, and Web Development teams to create and implement customized on-line media buys for advertisers.
- Coordinated ad tag implementation for mobile, video, social media, site redesign efforts with Web Development team and outside partners.

Education

Bachelor of Science: Business Management